A boy's journey. A mother's love. Miles of burning city between them.
Blitz is a war, drama, history film directed by Steve McQueen.
In World War II London, nine-year-old George is evacuated to the
countryside by his mother, Rita, to escape the bombings.
Defiant and determined to return to his family, George embarks on an
epic, perilous journey back home as Rita searches for him.
George, played by Elliott Heffernan.
Rita, played by Saoirse Ronan.
Ife, played by Benjamin Clementine.
Gerald, played by Paul Weller.
Albert, played by Stephen Graham.
Jack, played by Harris Dickinson.
Blitz  is a 2024 historical war drama film about WWII
written, produced and directed by Steve McQueen.
The film stars Saoirse Ronan and Elliott Heffernan (in his film debut), supported by Harris
Dickinson, Benjamin Clementine, Kathy Burke, Paul Weller, and Stephen Graham.
Blitz had its world premiere as the opening film at the BFI London Film Festival on 9 October 2024, and was released in selected cinemas in
the United Kingdom and United States on 1 November 2024, followed by a streaming release on Apple TV+ on 22 November 2024.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of factory, london,
england, world war ii, flooding, singer.
The tone is emotional and intense.